optmd.com 2012-12-11

# OptMD.com > Privacy Policy

|   
---  
  
|  |  |   
---  
| | 

**Privacy Policy (updated 05/01/09)** **What This Privacy Policy Covers  
** Optimax Media Delivery (OptMD) produced this privacy policy in an effort to demonstrate its firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices of OptMD. 

OptMD believes in all Internet users' rights to privacy. OptMD does not engage in any form of distribution or sale of Personally Identifiable information to third parties for their own promotional use, including but not limited to, names, email/postal addresses, and phone numbers. All information collected by OptMD is not personally identifiable as it relates to consumers, nor does OptMD engage in any form of consumer profiling. 

To inquire about privacy concerns, please contact OptMD by mail, as detailed below, or using our online form.

 **Optimax Media Delivery  
** 100 Wilshire Blvd. Suite 950  
Santa Monica, CA 90401  
USA

 **Cookies  
** A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a web site's computer and stored on your computer's hard drive. 

OptMD uses cookies for the purpose of tracking when an Internet user has seen an advertisement. These cookies do not and can not provide OptMD with any Personally Identifiable information about an Internet user. These cookies serve two purposes:

  1. They are used to inform OptMD whether or not an advertisement has been served to the same computer before, and if so, when the advertisement was served. These cookies are **not** used by OptMD to build a profile of a user's behaviour **nor** are they used by OptMD for the purposes of behavioural tracking or behavioural targeting. OptMD is one of the few online advertising networks that do **not** engage in the practice of behavioural targeting.
  2. They are used to facilitate retargeting at a campaign level. Retargeting occurs within the confines of a user-to-advertiser relationship, and is not available for general targeting on the network. 

OptMD uses both session and persistent cookies on our website. These are needed for site navigation and to perform aggregate analysis of what is viewed on our site. 

**Opt-Out  
** Consumers have the unrestricted ability to opt out of all OptMD paid advertising, cookies and tracking at any time by utilizing our opt out mechanism. In place of paid advertising, users who have opted out will receive unpaid, public service announcements (PSAs). Please click here to access our opt-out mechanism.

**Collection and Use of Non-Personally Identifiable Information  
** All information shared with both OptMD advertisers and publishers is done so in an aggregate fashion. This allows us to provide those who use our services with broad percentages regarding the users who are receiving advertisements delivered by OptMD. However, this data is not linked to any form of Personally Identifiable information. 

Information collected by advertisers on their websites who use OptMD may contain Personally Identifiable information. However, data such as this is provided by the individual Internet user in the form of online order forms, contests, or otherwise through the members website, not OptMD. This Personally Identifiable information collected outside OptMD is subject to the privacy policies of the individual advertisers involved. 

OptMD prides itself on providing an atmosphere that is non-disruptive to Internet users. Our proprietary targeting methodologies enable advertisers to effectively target their campaigns to the audience(s) they are looking to reach without engaging in profiling practices, which invade the privacy of Internet users. 

Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Collection and Use of Personally Identifiable Information  
** Inquies made to OptMD via our Contact Us form can include your full name and email address. We use this information to respond to inquiries. We hold all such information submitted in strict confidence. Under no circumstances will a user's email address or other Personally Identifiable information be sold to, supplied to, or otherwise made available to any third party. 

**Security  
** We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, please contact us using our online form.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

 **Changes to This Privacy Policy  
** OptMD may find it necessary to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any changes will be posted at this site. Except as otherwise required by law, any modifications made to this Privacy Policy will not materially affect the privacy of data collected by OptMD prior to the effective date of the policy change. 

|   
---|---|---  

|  | **[](http://iab.net/)Interactive Advertising Bureau  
**  
The IAB educates marketers, agencies, media companies and the wider business community about the value of interactive advertising. Working with its member companies, the IAB evaluates and recommends industry standards and practices.  
---|---  
  
CLICK TO   
OPT OUT » You must have cookies enabled on your browser for the opt out to take effect. If you clear your cookies, the opt out will be deleted and you will need to opt out again. Cookies are the only means by which we can control ad delivery.

**WARNING:** By opting out you are taking an active position not to support the pubilshers whose websites you visit and whose content you consume free of charge. In doing so you threaten the long term viability of their operations.
